

#### **FABCHI RAJOUR JUMFAN**

- ☐ fabchirajoul@gmail.com
  - +27 0844763356
- www.linkedin.com/in/rajourjumfan-fabchi-97a584212
  - 36 Ray Street Sophiatown Johannesburg

#### **EDUCATION**

2019-2022 BEng Tech Mining
Engineering University of
Johannesburg South Africa

2011-2015 BEng Telecommunications
Engineering University of
Buea Cameroon

2009-2011 Advance Level Certificate
Bilingual Grammar School
Molyko Buea Cameroon

2004-2009 Ordinary Level Certificate
Bilingual Grammar School
Molyko Buea Cameroon

1998-2004 First School Leaving and Common Entrance Government Bilingual Primary

#### **LEADERSHIP SKILLS**

- Treasurer of the
   University of Johannesburg
   Mining Forum from 2020 to
   2021
- Chairperson of the University of Johannesburg Mining Forum Adhoc Community
- chairperson of our Ex-Student association where under my leadership, the core objectives of the association was obtained
- Negotiation and leadership Skills

## **SUMMARY**

I possess a broad background in both mining and telecommunications engineering as well as an in-depth knowledge of the use of machine learning and artificial intelligence. My knowledge in data transfer, network and mine planning designs, communication system designs etc. is very extensive thanks to my degrees in mining and telecommunication. I have been able to integrate my technological expertise to build and create cutting edge solutions within the mining industry which is one of the reasons I embarked on attaining a degree in the mining field. One of such cutting-edge solutions has been to develop a multi-modal machine learning system that uses several regression and classifier algorithms to categorize and predict the maximum unsupported span using geological rock characteristics in a small-scale artisanal mine GitHub link: https://github.com/Fabchirajoul

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

03/2023 to Present

Software Developer at University of Johannesburg and Accenture South Africa Pty

- 4IR boot camp technologies (Machine learning).
- Developing bootcamp API widgets
- o Agile rapid skills acquisition
- 4IR Engineering business skills acquisition
- Full stack web development for 4IR
- Responsive web pages using handlebars with bootstrap and materialize frameworks
- MochaJs and ChaiJs testing of JavaScript functions
- o Building machine learning models in Jupiter and google collab notebook

06/2015 to 12/2018 Telecommunications Engineer at Viettel Cameroon SA Bamenda Cameroon

- o Investigated the effect of pulse broadening on optic fiber transmission.
- Responding to server alarms and emergency calls to detect intrusion and abnormalities, addressing internal processes.
- Utilized components and equipment to configure networks and integrate systems, supporting traffic flow and improving stability.
- Formulated network proposals and executed proposed solutions to identify and address bottlenecks causing performance problems.
- Maintained inventory of computer parts to keep accurate log and meet demands of required materials.
- Conducted data backups to preserve memory and information, promoting recovery during system failures.
- Used analog lines, SIP trunks and PRI systems to deliver multiple connection channels.
- Troubleshoot, and oversee construction and maintenance of telecommunications network systems
- Maintenance of BTS sub-systems
- Maintenance and designation of antennas in arrays
- Troubleshooting error logs in optic fiber lines

08/2014 to 05/2015 Telecommunications Engineer at Cameroon Radio Television Yaoundé, Cameroon

- o Maintenance of electrical and air conditioning systems
- Production and processing of TV transmission signals at dedicated radio frequencies
- Transmission of TV frequencies via satellite
- Retransmission and Broadcasting of TV signals
- Conducted data backups to preserve memory and information, promoting recovery during system failures.

# French English

## **BUSINESS SKILLS**

- Very dynamic and business oriented and successfully ran an investment in agriculture for three years (2015 to 2019) ensuring proper management skills, citing strength and weaknesses.
- Presently running a successful business (2019 to date) in automobiles in the buying and selling of cars with reasonable success so far

### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

- Golden Key Award Issued by Golden Key International Honor Society: April 2022
- Top Achievers Award Issued by University of Johannesburg August 2019
- Best Employee of the year award Issued by Viettel Cameroon SA December 2018

# HOBBIES

- Sports (Soccer)
- Reading and developing ideas
- Music (Gospel)
- Coding (Programming Languages)

#### KEY ATTRIBUTES

- Good communication skills
- Can work under pressure, night shift and overtime
- Good leadership skills
- Can work in a team as well as individually
- Ability to work under minimum or no supervision
- Can work overtime as well as night shift
- Translating/ interpreting skills
- Fast learner/ hard worker
- Trustworthy
- o Punctual
- Attention to detail

#### **SKILLS**

- o API Development
- Data Manipulation
- Presentation Skills
- Data Analysis
- Express.js
- Application Programming Interfaces (API)
- Node.js
- o SQL
- Data Analytics
- Interpersonal Skills
- Back-End Web Development
- Database Design
- o Web Development
- o React.is
- Mocha (JavaScript Framework)
- o Bootstrap (Framework) · Materialize (Framework)
- o Git · Agile Methodologies
- Problem Solving
- Presentations
- Artificial Intelligence (AI)
- Machine Learning
- Network Configuration
- Communication · Telecommunications
- o Antenna Design
- Signal Processing
- Digital Signal Processors
- o signal transmission
- Signal retransmission
- Data Backup Solutions
- Strategic planning
- Project scheduling
- Safety Inspection
- Project calculations
- Geotechnical rock analysis
- o Financial valuation and modeling
- Microsoft Excel
- Mine Planning and design

# OTHER INTERACTION/ACTIVITIES THAT YOU TAKE PART IN WITHIN THE EDUCATIONAL JOURNEY

I have been a voluntary tutor to all my classmates and juniors within the department. With my vast knowledge and quick understanding of the subject matter, I was able to act as a mediator between my lecturers and classmates. All through the years of 2020, 2021 and 2022, due to the outbreak of Corona virus, I would organize zoom sessions to further explain to classmates and junior students which helped improved the overall passed percentage of the entire.

# WHAT DO YOU FORESEE YOURSELF CONTRIBUTING TO WITHIN THE MINING INDUSTRY?

I foresee my contribution to the mining industry as bringing in new ideas and opinions. I have successfully developed a multi-modal machine learning model that successfully predicts the maximum unsupported span for a small-scale artisanal mine and built a front-end user interface using NodeJs and Python-Shell for user interactions linked with the machine learning model which is just the beginning of my contributions to the mining industry using machine learning and artificial intelligence.